Nicola Jeffery

UI/UX Designer

Profile

UI Designer with a background in Merchandise Planning with a focus of Digital. Vast experience within E-Commerce, including managing and influencing conversion rates, demand generation and content marketing. Extremely successful in communicating the vision to audiences of varying backgrounds, managing multiple projects, working across large cross-functional teams and managing complex business situations in an analytical yet creative manner.

- 07742150915
- @ nicolajeffery6@gmail.com
- London
- www.nicolajeffery.com

Skills

- Branding / Visual Design
- Competitor Research and Analysis
- · User Research
- User Personas
- User Flows
- Low, Mid and High-Fidelity Wireframes
- Prototyping
- · Usability Analysis
- Frontend Development
- Project Management

Tools

- Adobe XD
- Figma
- InVision
- Usability Hub
- Google Analytics
- · Shopify
- · Microsoft Office

Education

UI Design Certificate 2022 - Career Foundry

BA(Hons) Business Studies &

Economics - First Class 2014 - The Open University

Experience

Digital Merchandise Planning Manager - Levi Strauss & co Remote UK - February 2022 - Present

- Management of the Merchandise Planning of all UK and Europe Dockers' Digital Accounts.
- Ownership of the Merchandise Planning and trading of the Dockers' UK and European website, driving growth of +50% vs LY.
- · Management of the Digital Wholesale Merchandise Planner.

Digital Merchandise Planner - Levi Strauss & co Remote UK - April 2021 - February 2022

- Ownership of the Merchandise Planning and trading of all UK and Europe Dockers' Digital Accounts.
- Driving growth of +50% on owned and operated websites and +70% of Digital Key Accounts.

Merchandise Planning / Product Merchandiser - Burberry London UK - August 2019 - April 2021

- Providing experienced Merchandise Planning and Product Merchandising support to the Global Team.
- Successfully created and introduced new ways of working processes improving efficiency and performance during the turbulent Covid 19 trading.

Assistant Merchandiser - Fenwick

London UK - October 2018 - April 2019

- Ownership of the Merchandise Planning and Trading of the Men's Accessories and Loungewear business.
- Successfully built the Merchandise Planning team and processes where previously no Merchandising team existed.
- Drove growth of +5% on the year whilst total company in decline.

Assistant Merchandiser - Harrods

London UK - February 2017 - July 2018

 Ownership of departments with yearly trade £52M and assisting on departments generating £100M+.

Trainee Merchandiser - Primark

Reading UK - November 2014 - February 2017

 Taking ownership of 3 key departments with yearly trade totalling £27M.